Daniel Hanks Jr

204 Kingsdown Drive - Liverpool, NY 13088 315-944-7574 | <u>dhanksjr@twcny.rr.com</u>

https://dphanksjr.github.io/main/

SUMMARY

Experienced IT professional with a broad knowledge of hardware, software, and networking technologies. Proficient in database design and development, software design, programming and debugging. Newly acquired skills in the Data Science field extracting and analyzing data, turning it into useful information and then visualizing it.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming: Python (scikit-learn, numpy, scipy, pandas, nltk), R, SQL, ASP.NET, C++, C#, HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, XML, XSLT
- Software: Visual Studio, SQL Server, MySQL, SharePoint, Microsoft Office, Adobe Creative Suite, Expressions, Contribute, VMware, GIT, IIS, Apache, Tomcat
- Operating Systems: CentOS/Ubuntu, Windows 2000/XP/Vista/7,8, Windows 2000/2003/2008 Server, OS X
- **Networking:** Active Directory, Novell, Citrix, LAN, WAN, TCP/IP, WINS, DHCP, DNS, Cisco IOS, VLAN, Routing Protocols (OSPF, EIGRP, IGRP, RIP), ACL implementation, VPNs

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Syracuse University Libraries, Syracuse NY

2/2014 - Present

IT Analyst/Programmer

- Planned, customized, developed, designed and tested library web applications in LAMP environment.
- Wrote scripts to Import, export and retrieve data from various sources for storage and display.
- Installed, evaluated, implemented, and customized open source web software.
- Created system and software documentation as needed for new and existing systems
- Recommend changes to existing systems and implement new systems as needed.
- Reviewed requests for system modifications and analyzed the complexity, scope, and feasibility of implementing the changes.

Bryant & Stratton College, Liverpool, NY

5/2010 -3/2014

Syracuse, NY

9/2016-Present

Part-time Evening Adjunct Instructor in Networking Technology

Responsible for teaching students in a hands-on computer lab environment that prepares them for A+, Network+, Cisco and Microsoft certifications. Examples of skills taught to them include:

- Installing, configuring, troubleshooting, and securing networks.
- Managing users and sharing resources.
- Working with network and routing protocols.
- Researching, evaluating, recommending and specifying hardware and software components and complete systems for enterprise needs.

Loretto, Syracuse, NY

10/2012-2/2014

Analyst/Programmer

- Analyzed user requests to determine parameters of required program and if a new program must be created or if an existing program can be modified.
- Designed, coded, tested, maintained and documented complex programs based on user requests.
- Built complex user interface applications and back-end databases using various web development tools, programming languages and scripting languages.

- Prepared user and technical documentation for implementation and support.
- Analyzed and documented user information needs or business problems and determined most effective/efficient programming solutions.

Falk College of Sport & Human Dynamics, Syracuse NY

3/2006 - 10/2012

Computer Consultant

- Designed, programmed and supported college website using ASP.NET, C# and JavaScript.
- Created and updated websites for student groups.
- Built forms that would gather recruiting information and assist in scheduling classes.
- Created master pages to speed up development of web site.
- Wrote and modified databases that utilized SQL.
- Organized and instructed group training sessions on a variety of applications.
- Administered Microsoft Windows Servers (Active Directory), Novell Servers and Microsoft Workstations

Bryant & Stratton College, Liverpool, NY

4/2001 -3/2006

Technology Coordinator

- Setup and managed Windows2003/XP, Novell NetWare and Peer-to-Peer networks
- Implemented Active Directory and Citrix environment for college
- Lead group training sessions on various software applications with faculty and staff
- Developed and implemented backup recovery systems using programs such as ArcServeIT and Norton Ghost Enterprise
- Established and maintained network users and security
- Loaded and updated application software such as Oracle Applications, Office 2003/XP, and virus scan software
- Managed inventory of hardware and software, including licensees
- Maintained vendor relations

CC Plus, N. Syracuse, NY

8/1999 - 4/2001

Computer Consultant

- Designed, created and modified web pages using HTML, Java, PHP, MySQL and programs such as Macromedia Flash, Adobe Photoshop and Dreamweaver
- Created databases and applications in Access and Visual Basic that utilized SQL
- Setup web servers and RAS servers using Windows 2000/NT and IIS 4.0/5.0
- Installed and configured routers and firewalls

EDUCATION

Syracuse University – School of Information Studies

CAS in Data Science

Relevant Courses: Data Mining, Data Administration Concepts and Database Management, Applied Data Science and Information Visualization

Bellevue University

MS-Management of Information Systems, 2010 -Information Security Concentration

CERTIFICATIONS

Cisco Certified Network Associate (CCNA) (Expired 2014) Security + (Expired 2014)